

IT Analyst seeking roles in Software Engineering, Software Development, Application Support, Project Management, Change Management, Quality Management, Requirement Gathering, Pega Rules Process Commander, JavaScript, Pega PRPC, MySQL, HTML, Unix, XML, C, C++



Current Designation: IT Analyst Total Experience: 8 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Tata Consultancy Services Ltd.

Notice Period: Currently Serving Notice Period

Current Location: Pune Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Ahmedabad, Mumbai, Pune

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: IT Analyst, Software Developer, Software Engineering, Software Development, Application Support, Project

Management, Change Management, Quality Management, Requirement Gathering, Pega Rules Process

Commander, JavaScript, Pega PRPC, MySQL, HTML, Unix, XML, C, C++

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

Working in Tata Consultancy Services Limited (TCSL) as IT Analyst from August 2016 in banking and healthcare domain Pega PRPC development projects. Having a total of 7+ years of experience in Pega PRPC and 8+ years of IT experience. Hands on experience on PegaRULES Process Commander (PRPC) and possess BFSI and Healthcare domain knowledge. Have been involved in coordinating with clients, designing, developing & reviewing deliverables, and ensuring compliance to quality.

Work Experience

Tata Consultancy Services Ltd. as IT Analyst

Aug 2016 to Till Date

Organization TATA Consultancy Services

Description Worked on the development of SRSD (Single Reference Safety Document) application. Involved with the development of multiple modules within the application, along with providing the estimates of the efforts. Worked in the PEGA PRPC v7.3 version.

Roles & Responsibilities * Worked on the development of the applications from the beginning

- * Understood the client requirements and the requirement documents and helped the team in estimating the efforts for the development
- * Analyzed the business requirements and developed the modules as per the requirements.
- * Prepared design document.
- * Made the code changes and did code review of fellow team members' components.
- * Unit testing and System testing are done to make the system more reliable and error free.
- * Prepared Unit Test Plan to document the unit test cases which was used during unit testing and system testing of the system.
- * Coordinating with the other teams and helped the testing team

Achievements * Received recognition from the clients on delivering the components on time.

Solution Environment Pega Rules Process Commander V 7.3, MySQL SQL Developer.

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=d9e9831178169acb1961982a13f224c4590c5a594d470c400744400b09...

Project CLM (Client Lifecycle Management)

Customer One of the Leading Banks (Banking domain)

Period Sep 2016 - Oct 2019

Organization TATA Consultancy Services

Description Worked on the development of CLM(Client Lifecycle Management) application which includes the onboarding, KYC, Regulatory, Products and Off-boarding of the clients. Along with the development of the application working on the enhancements and provided with L3 support post the application went live. Involved with the development of multiple modules within the application like request initiation, regulatory certifications, account setups. Worked in the PEGA PRPC v7.3 version.

Roles & Responsibilities Worked on the development of the applications from the beginning

- Understood the client requirements and the requirement documents and helped the team in estimating the efforts for the development
- Analyzed the business requirements and developed the modules as per the requirements.
- Prepared design document.
- Made the code changes and did code review of fellow team members' components.
- Unit testing and System testing are done to make the system more reliable and error free.
- Prepared Unit Test Plan to document the unit test cases which was used during unit testing and system testing of the system.
- Coordinating with the other teams and helped the testing team.
- Provided with L3 support post the production releases, worked on the enhancements and new development alongside.

Accenture as Software Engineer

Dec 2014 to Jul 2016

Project Scorecard, Separation of Duties

One of the Leading Banks of U.S.A.(Banking domain) Customer

Period Jan 2015 - Jul 2016 Organization Accenture

Scorecard is an application based on Pega System Inc. BPM Tool PRPC. It is an application that is used by Description the bank for the management of the resources such as hardware, software, users, performance of the systems. The application would generate the reports for the same and the admins have the access to either add or modify the data. The application was applicable for the production environment, Low level environments and the Development environments. The reports were generated for RAM utilization, CUP utilization, Concurrent Users, LOB Users etc. There were 14 different reports for each of the environments.

Separation of Duties (SOD) is an application for the internal use of the bank as an asset which should generate reports so that the Separation of Duties is not violated. Here the users having access to one environment should not have access to the other environments, for example the development user should not have access to the production environment and vice versa. The user can log into the application and generate the reports for the duration he wants. The application also generates weekly and quarterly reports of the users who violate the separation of duties and send it to the admin team. Roles & Responsibilities * Worked on the development of the applications from the beginning

- Understood the client requirements and the requirement documents and helped the team in estimating the efforts for the development
- Analyzed the business requirements and developed the modules as per the requirements.
- Prepared design document.
- Made the code changes and did code review of fellow team members' components.
- Unit testing and System testing are done to make the system more reliable and error free.
- Prepared Unit Test Plan to document the unit test cases which was used during unit testing and system testing of the system.
- Coordinating with the other teams and helped the testing team.

Achievements Received recognition from the clients on delivering the components on time.

Pega Rules Process Commander V 6.2, MySQL SQL Developer. Solution Environment

Project PegaRULES Platform Upgrade to V7

Customer One of the Leading Banks of U.S.A.(Banking domain)

Organization Accenture

Period Jan. 2016 - Jul. 2016

Description Pega System Inc. releases new versions of PRPC with new features, enhanced existing features, better stability in terms of performance and efficiency. The Bank will upgrade its PRPC related systems across board with new version within the year of new version release from Pega System Inc.

The Intent of this TPR is to upgrade PRPC V6.x to V7 released by Pega System Inc.

Upgraded various applications of the bank.

Roles & Responsibilities * Was responsible for the compliance level upgrade to V7.

- * After addressing to hundreds of sections and deprecated rules and making changes for the compliance upgrade to V7 to make the applications HTML 5 compliant.
- * Service Requests (SRs) will be raised to Pega Systems for system issues.
- * Made the code changes to make the application V7.1 compliant wherever necessary.
- * Unit testing and System testing were done to make the system more reliable and error free after the upgrades.
- * Prepared Unit Test Plan to document the unit test cases which was used during unit testing and system testing of the system.

Dell International Services Ltd. as Senior Associate

Jul 2011 to Jul 2013

Project Process Integrator Employment, Smart Invoice Processing
Customer Leading Chain of Hospitals in the U.S.A. (Healthcare Domain)

Organization Dell Services, Bangalore

Period Sep. 2011 to July 2013

Description Process Integrator Employment (P.I.E.) is an application which is used by the hospitals to onboard a new Doctor or an Employee. The application was used by all the hospitals in the chain across the United States of America. Depending on the doctor, the specialization, the location there were different levels of approval for onboarding.

Smart Invoice Processing is an application in which all the invoices for the hospitals for the different utilities such as Electricity, Water, Utilities and all the invoices which needed approvals were handled. The hard copies of the invoices would be scanned by SMART and the invoices would be created in Pega. Depending on the type and amount of the invoice the different approvers and different levels of approvers are needed. Once the invoices get approved then the funds get released.

Worked on the development of various modules of this application.

Roles & Responsibilities * Analyzed the business requirements and functionalities and developed the modules for the applications.

- * Understood the client requirements and the requirement documents and helped the team in estimating the efforts for the development.
- * Developed various modules for the applications.
- Prepared design document to incorporate the functionalities.
- * Made the code changes and did code review of fellow team members' components.
- * Unit testing and System testing were done to make the system more reliable and error free.
- * Prepared Unit Test Plan to document the unit test cases which was used during unit testing and system testing of the system.
- * Coordinated with the other teams and helped the testing team with full integration testing. Achievements * Have received Spot Award for on time delivery of components.

Solution Environment Pega Rules Process Commander V 6.2, MySQL

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Nitte Meenakshi Institute of Technology, Bangalore in 2011

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

System Architect

Pega CSA

IT Skills

Skill Name Version Last Used Experience

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=d9e9831178169acb1961982a13f224c4590c5a594d470c400744400b09...

Windows XP/Vista/7/10, UNIX	
C/C++, HTML, XML, JavaScript	
PRPC V6.1, V6.2, V7.1, V7.3,	
Visual Engineer	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Gujarati				

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent / Temporary

Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time